GLENDY TUYUC

Web Developer

+502-5612-6256 | glendytuyuc@gmail.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/glendy-tuyuc

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Dedicated, committed, responsible and with a great capacity for learning. Proactive team player with a strong background in customer service and web development. With more than a year of being self-taught learning programing languages such as **JavaScript**, with frameworks like, **React JS**, **Next JS**, **Typescript**, **CSS**, and **Tailwind CSS** in the Front-End Development, **Express**, **Node JS**, in the Back End Development. **MongoDB**, **Postgres** for Database. Expertise to create **Rest API's**. **Git**, **GitHub** for version control, **Jest** for Unit Testing, **Playwright** for E2E test. **Docker** to distributed microservices architectures, and highly scalable data processing systems. Always focusing on delivering the best solutions in every situation having another point of view improving and optimizing every task given.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Freelancer

2024 – present

 Web pages from scratch to generate personalized and downloadable tickets. Pages created using HTML5, Tailwind CSS, JavaScript, React JS, TypeScript, Zustand, using Hooks, like useState, useRef, useContext, and useEffect. Fully interactive and responsive for computers, tablets and smartphones.

Customer Service Supervisor Alorica Limitada Guatemala Guatemala, Guatemala January 2023 – March 2023

- Coordinate complex problem solving, demonstrating problem-solving skills.
- Provide guidance and support to the team to ensure high-quality customer service.
- Participate in continuous improvement initiatives to increase customer satisfaction.

Customer Service Agent Alorica Limitada Guatemala Guatemala, Guatemala 2020 – 2023

- Provide support to customers through various channels, such as phone and live chat.
- Resolve issues and complaints effectively, ensuring customer retention.
- Collaborate with other departments to improve customer service processes.
- Twice named Top Performer in customer service.

EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS

• Typescript Developer Bootcamp Laserants – 28 Hours of learning and putting into practice, JavaScript, Typescript, GitHub Actions, Express, Prisma, Postgres, Turborepo, Docker, Jest for Unit Test, and Playwright for End 2 End Test. Creating an e-Commerce from scratch, developing the Rest API, to create, read, update and deleting data,

connecting the database with the Backend with Prisma ORM and Express, using Typescript and Tailwind CSS for the Front-End.

- UDEMY [React & Typescript The Complete Guide: Hooks, Context, Redux, MERN]
 [2023 Completed]
- EF SET English Certificate B2 Upper Intermediate. Expedicion: junio 2024. ID de la credencial jKhzD1
- Systems Engineering
 [Mariano Gálvez University of the Department of Chimaltenango, Guatemala - UMG] [January 2023 1st Semester – June 2023] Still in the process to achieve it.
- Bachelor's Degree in Commercially Oriented Computing [Centro Educativo Formación y Ciencia in San Juan Comalapa, Chimaltenango] [2018 2019]

SOFT SKILLS

- Customer Service
- Effective Communication skills
- Problem-solving skills and critical thinking
- Customer Relationship Management
- Teamwork
- Self-learning
- Time management

LANGUAGES

- Spanish: Native
- English: Upper Intermediate Level B2

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- HTML
- CSS
- JAVASCRIPT
- REACT JS
- REACT
- REDUX
- TYPESCRIPT
- NEXT JS
- TAILWIND
- BOOTSTRAP
- GIT
- GITHUB
- GITHUB ACTIONS

- MYSQL
- POSTGRES
- MONGO DB
- DOCKER
- EXPRESS
- PRISMA
- NODE JS
- JEST
- PLAYWRIGHT